Sankar Venkatesan

Automation Test Engineer

Over 6 years of experience in both manual and automated software Quality Assurance Testing of web-based applications testing, Object-oriented analysis design with in-depth understanding. Extensive Knowledge of Quality Assurance standards, methodologies, and strategies with a better understanding of the Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC).

Contact

Phone

+917550309189

E-mail

shankarvenkatesan59@gmail.com

Skills

Testing Types: Manual

Testing, Automation testing, API Testing, Mobile Testing (Android & IOS), Functional

Testing

Testing Tools: Selenium WebDriver, PlayWright,

Appium

Project and Bug Tracking

Tools: JIRA, notion

Programming Languages:

Core Java

Version Control Tool: GIT,

GitHub

Dependency Management

Tool: Maven

CI/CD Tools: Jenkins

Testing Framework:

Cucumber, TestNG, Data Driven Testing, POM, APITesting(Postman, Rest Assured).

Work History

Automation Test Engineer

Publicis Sapient (Aug 2021-Till Date)

Norizen Soft Solutions(April 2019- July 2021)

- Extensive experience in developing and maintaining, executing scripts written using Selenium WebDriver and PlayWright with JAVA for the automation of web applications and Appium (Android & IOS) for automation of mobile applications.
- Good experience in using Singleton Design Pattern.
- Worked on Cucumber BDD using POM well versed with Feature files, StepDefenition.
- Worked on Apache POI store adding data from external sources preferably an Excel sheet to feed locators into the test script.
- Good working experience in building management tools like
 Maven, automating and scheduling test execution
- Expertise in Hybrid Framework using Data Driven approach based on Page Object Model design pattern and TestNG.
- Experience working in various frameworks like Data Driven framework.
- Experience in identifying different page elements using object locators and creating **an Object repository** for all the pages.
- Maintained the Selenium WebDriver, Java automation code, and resources in source control GitHub.
- Exposure JDBC and SQL commands.
- Well-versed with XPath, Document Object Model (DOM).
- Self-Acquired knowledge in API testing Postman & Rest Assured.
- Experience in all phases of the Software Testing Life Cycle (STLC).
- Exposure to Agile Methodology and well-versed with terms like Scrum, Sprint, Product Backlog, Sprint Backlog, and Sprint Retrospective.
- Having good exposure in **CICD** tools like **Jenkins**.
- Capable of working with a team as well as individual.
- Engage in client calls and meetings on a daily base.

Education

B.E(EEE) CGPA: 7

IFET College of Engineering

Aug 2015 - Apr 2019

#1 Project Summary

Project Title: Axon Oct 2024-Till Date

Description:

Axon is a sleek and modern name that conveys speed, agility, and high performance—perfect for a sports shoe brand. The word "Axon" is inspired by the biological term for nerve fibers that transmit signals quickly, symbolizing fast reflexes, precision, and high energy.

Tools Used: Selenium, PlayWright, Java, Appium, Cucumber, Postman, Restassured, GIT, JIRA

Key Roles:

- Coordinated with peers in the team for clarity on the requirements
- Implementautomation tests across both Weband Mobile(Android & IOS).
- Have experience in training people who have no automation experience but have strong programming skills.
- Understand test plan document and analyses the schedule
- Analyzing the **Feasibility of Test automation** and provide estimation for automation effort
- Preparing the Featurefile, Step Definition, Hooks, POM, Utilityclass in CUCUMBER framework
- Execution of automated Test scripts through Maven Projects
- Performing Defect Tracking & Management in JIRA and generated automated daily reports using JIRA
- Creating regression test suites for the identified tests
- Rerun the failed test cases
- Regression testing configured in **Jenkins**
- Execution of **Smoke**, **Sanity** and **Regression** suites during new releases and analyses the test failure

#2 Project Summary

Project Title: Selfridges April 2023-August 2024

Description:

Selfridges is an e-commerce retailer application, buying or selling of products on online services over the internet.

Tools Used: Core Java, Selenium, Appium, Cucumber, GIT, JIRA, Postman

Key Roles:

- Developing and executing the test scripts using Cucumber.
- Dynamically used **Junit, POM, Data Driven** and many other reusable methods from **Base class** with one another to perform Automation testing
- Analyze the user stories and understanding them thoroughly.
- Activelyinvolved in preparing of **TestData** for Framework.

- Understanding of an API and Creation of tests to verify the business logic works and to ensure that different services can communicate with each other
- Used **GitHub** source code management tool for code re-usage, high portability extending scope of Automation Testing.

#3 Project Summary

Project Title: Ocado Sep 2021-Feb 2023

Description:

Ocado is a British online supermarket that describes itself as the world's largest dedicated online grocery retailer in contrast to its main competitors, the company has no chain of stores and does all home deliveries from its warehouses.

Tools Used: Core Java, Selenium WebDriver, TestNG, GIT, JIRA

Key Roles:

- Prepared Test Plan, test Cases, Test scripts for the application based on the functional requirements, portal redesigned and test specs.
- Worked in an Agile environment, with the ability to accommodate and test the newly proposed changes at any point of time during the release.
- Evaluate and analyze Business Requirements, Functional Specification documents.
- Developed and executed test plans, and test cases utilizing QA best practices and standards.
- Designed, developed, and implemented automation testing framework utilizing Java,
 TestNG and Selenium Web Driver.
- Involved in designing and implementing of hybrid automation framework to be used with **Selenium Web Driver**.
- Created Test plan, High level scenarios, test case construction and test estimates, resource estimates and weekly status reports.
- Daily schedule the run batch for testing.
- Attending defect calls with developers and clients to enhance the project.
- Defect logging & tracking in Test Management tool using JIRA.
- Participating in all the Agile ceremonies Sprint Planning, Daily scrum calls, Sprint review and Sprint retrospective.

#4 Project Summary

Project Title: OneGreen Nov 2020- July 2021

Description:

OneGreen is Asia's largest one-stop shop/marketplace for natural and sustainable products. The product categories range from personal care, baby care, groceries, intimate hygiene, home care, responsible apparel and clothing.

Tools Used: Core Java, Selenium WebDriver, TestNG, GIT, JIRA

#5 Project Summary

Project Title: WizzAir

June2019- Oct 2020

Description:

WizzAir is a Hungarian low-cost Airline. This airline serves across 44 countries and also serves many cities across Europe as well as some destination like North Africa.

Tools Used: Core Java, Selenium WebDriver, TestNG, GIT, JIRA

Key Roles:

- Analysed the Business Requirements and Functional specifications within the team for business understanding and end-user focus.
- Worked with the Business Analysis Team to prepare detailed Test plans and Test Cases for the enhancements of the Business user.
- Analysing the User Stories and planning the User Stories to be completed in the particular sprint.
- Test manually and identify the defects.
- Identified test cases to automate.
- Automate those test cases using Selenium WebDriver, TestNG and Java (Eclipse IDE).
- Contributed in framework creation.
- Uploaded test cases in JIRA and executed test cases and logged defects.
- Also performed Functional and Regression testing.
- Defect logging & tracking in Test Management tool using JIRA which were found at execution time.
- Retest the defects once they have been resolved an updated defect report.
- Performed manual tests to conduct functional, system, integration regression on the application.
- Involved in executing automated test cases using Selenium WebDriver to automate manual testing solutions.
- Owned up an entire module and prepared defects summary report of that particular module for reporting a daily triage call with developers to get it fixed on time.

Declaration

I hereby declare the above-mentioned details are true and correct to the best of my knowledge.

Date:

Place: Chennai (Sankar Venkatesan)